[THEME MUSIC PLAYING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
[ENGINE REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TRUCK HORN BLARES]
[LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- Stop!
- [GUNSHOT]
[FIREWORKS EXPLODING]
- [ENGINES REVVING]
- [BUS HORN HONKS]
[GLASS SHATTERING]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[ENGINES REVVING]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
- [GUNSHOT]
- [TIRES SCREECHING]
- [TRUCK HORN HONKS]
- [LOUD CRASH]
[TIRES SCREECHING]
I'm accepting my suspension
because I deserve it.
I just have a few suggestions
for the people we've arrested.
Why don't we put Mr. Chan
and Tiger in the same cell?
They're aggressive spiders
trapped in a box.
What, one small reporter
beat you all up?
It's not the reporter
who beat us up.
If you've just followed
what I told you,
they wouldn't have failed!
I'll make him pay!
I'm going to file
a police report.
Sir, this way. Follow me.
Damn it.
He got terribly lucky.
Look at what your son did
to the motorcycle.
I saved someone, that's why
the motorcycle got ruined.
The man I saved gave me money.
Here. It's for--
Come on, son.
Take it. It's yours.
This is not a good day
for Sam.
- Let's go for some drinks!
- Yes?
It's a yes!
Treat your friends.
They helped you big time.
- Salvador!
- Sir.
Looks like you still come
to us when you have a problem.
Well, you're involved in this!
You want to get revenge
because of my reports.
Watch your mouth.
Who even are you
for us to retaliate?
Admit it or not...
Who wants me beat up?
Who wants me killed?
Was it your men?
You keep making accusations
when you have no evidence.
There is no such thing
as police brutality.
But there is reporter brutality.
Hey, hey, hey, hey, hey!
Calm down! Calm down!
[ESTRELLA] Ma'am.
The reporter's here. Salvador.
- He's beaten up!
- Why?
He's here to file
a police report.
Come on. Let's go.
[SALVADOR] You want evidence?
[JACKET THUDS]
Fine, here! Watch this!
[BLOWS LANDING OVER PHONE]
Well? Well?
Surprised?
Your faces look guilty.
Or maybe your boss is
involved in this, too,
that General Jacinto!
That's just a video!
You still have no proof
we ordered that.
You've got to be careful
with your words, you know?
We can sue you for slander!
That's what you do best!
You keep scaring those
who go against you, right?
Luckily, a man saved me.
[SCOFFS]
Sir Salvador!
Are you here to ask us
to help you?
Or are you trying to prove
that you are our enemy?
[JACKET FLUTTERS]
Hey! Jacinto, huh?
What's your relation to that
heartless General Jacinto?
General Jacinto...
...is my father.
Well, that's it!
You know the answer!
Why ask me?
You should know the answer
if you have this.
A brain!
I can tolerate you
raising your voice.
But never slander my father.
What? You all planned
to have me killed?
The truth will come out!
I won't leave you alone.
I'll get my revenge.
I'll get my revenge!
[FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
[MAX] Sir.
What was Salvador saying?
Someone wants him dead?
Don't believe
that reporter's words.
All he says is fake news!
Sir, please
let me handle this case.
I'll prove to him that
what he's saying is wrong.
This is not even journalism.
It's fiction!
No, Lieutenant Jacinto.
It's pointless.
The report will just be biased
because of your last name.
Sir.
Shouldn't we check what the
people are complaining about?
Of course, we'll investigate.
Umali, Santos,
you handle the case.
- Yes, sir!
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
- [UMALI] Sir.
- What the hell?!
Is what I'm asking you
to do difficult?
- Was it that hard?!
- Hold on, sir!
- Sir, please!
- Don't touch me!
I just found out about it too.
It's just Salvador.
A low-rate reporter.
Now he has evidence against us!
Sir, don't worry.
I'll talk to Paquito.
I'll go back to Ginintuang Lupa
and find out what happened.
Find out what happened.
- Am I clear?
- Yes, sir.
But, sir...
Will we say that we're the ones
who had Salvador beaten up?
We're the ones who asked
Salvador to be beaten up, right?
Use your brain!
Whoever saved Salvador
is the reason why we're
in trouble right now!
Find out who he is.
Okay?
Alright, sir.
I'm just making it clear,
so I understand, sir.
You little--
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES, FADES]
[BOKBOK] I'm hungry, Kulot.
Aren't we going
to cash these out yet?
This stuff we gathered
still isn't enough.
We need more
so we can buy food.
I'm really hungry, Curly.
I haven't eaten since yesterday.
[BINOY] Where will
you treat us, Gabi?
- [GABO CHUCKLES]
- [TOLITS] Somewhere fancy!
I should've changed
into a killer outfit!
- [BONG] Oh no...
- [LAUGHTER]
Killer outfit? More like
an outfit for the dead.
[LAUGHTER]
I know you all,
you're all big eaters!
- Especially you!
- [LAUGHTER]
I know that Gabo
said that he'll treat us,
but don't abuse it.
He still has bills to pay.
[IPE] Let's just be grateful
that Gabo is treating us.
Hey, Curly, look!
Look!
Let's go!
[TENSE PLAYFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
- [WOMAN] Hey!
- [CHILD] She's coming!
[WOMAN] Stop that!
Hey, you thieves!
- Give those back!
- [CHILDREN LAUGHS]
Come back here, you thieves!
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
[WOMAN] Come back here,
you thieves!
Help me!
Those kids stole my goods!
These kids!
[WOMAN] You shameless kids!
[CHILDREN SHOUTING]
[WOMAN] Stop them!
Where the hell
are your parents?!
- [CHILDREN CRYING]
- [LOUD SLAP]
That's enough, please!
- [CHILDREN CRYING]
- [WOMAN] You thieves!
[LOUD SLAP]
[CHILDREN CRYING]
Stop!
What's going on?!
[WOMAN] Gabo,
mind your own business.
Those kids stole from me!
[MELANCHOLIC MUSIC PLAYING]
[FOREBODING MUSIC PLAYING]
How much was it?
I'll pay for it.
200 pesos! Give it to me now!
[TEKLA] I don't think
it's that much. She's bluffing.
Here.
I'm sorry.
The next time those kids
try to steal from me again,
they'll get a good beating!
I'm really sorry.
- [FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
- [BINOY] What a cranky lady.
Are you okay?
You kids alright?
I'm fine.
[TEKLA] You kids are going
to get an earful.
Come here.
Why did you do that?
Why did you steal food?
Gabo, we haven't eaten anything.
Our parents
haven't given us food.
But you shouldn't steal.
You know it's bad.
We didn't want to steal these.
But we haven't eaten
since last night.
[MELLOW MUSIC PLAYING]
- Fine.
- [KID SNIFFLES]
But you have to promise
not to do it again.
- Yes, Gabo!
Here.
I'm giving you money.
Buy something to eat.
If there's any left,
bring it home.
If you need something
or you're hungry, just find me.
Okay?
- Yes, Gabo!
Here. Go home.
- Come on, hurry!
- Get going, kids. Go home.
Gabo,
you're a completely
different man.
You've changed so much.
You were just like
those kids before,
running around with Django.
I learned a lot from prison.
I know how hard life inside was.
I don't want those kids
to do the same bad things
I've done.
Exactly! Gabo's right.
We shouldn't be tolerating
the kids' wrongdoings.
We're the adults.
We should be teaching them
good manners
and right conduct, am I right?
- Let's go.
- It's time for a drink.
- [CHEERING]
- [UPBEAT MUSIC PLAYING]
That 500 pesos
was supposed to be for drinks.
Let it go!
Those are for the kids!
You're so selfish.
[TRAFFIC NOISE]
[KNOB CLICKS, DOOR OPENS]
- Oli.
- Salvador.
[PENSIVE MUSIC PLAYING]
[JACKET THUDS]
Hey, hey, man!
What's that on your face?
What happened to you?
What do you think?
I went to the salon.
I had a makeover.
I got beaten up.
Oh god.
[TAPS DOOR] Salvador!
What took you so long?
We've been waiting for hours!
It's only the first day
of taping,
and you're already
acting like a diva.
Boss, boss. Look, look.
He got beaten up.
He got in trouble.
- Who did to you?
- [OLI CLEARS THROAT]
A group of criminals.
They ganged up and attacked me.
Luckily, a man helped me.
It's our pilot episode today!
You can't be on camera
looking like that!
Didn't you hear me, boss?
I was assaulted!
I almost got killed.
All because of the news
you asked me to report.
That's it.
That's the grit I want.
Courageous.
That's what the country needs.
That's what
the masses want, Salvador.
Exactly that!
You're so freaking cute!
Perfect!
Do exactly like that!
[PENSIVE MUSIC CONTINUES]
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- [CLEARS THROAT]
Deborah and I are going
to the NCIA office.
Come with us.
But you don't have to go in.
Just keep an eye outside.
Yes, sir.
I will get the cars ready.
- [DOOR OPENS]
- [FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
[SOMBER MUSIC PLAYING]
[EXHALES] Pa.
I failed to get back
at Mr. Chan.
But I'll try again.
I've heard that before, Lucas.
Don't be all talk.
Do it.
Pa...
give me another chance.
[GLASS THUDS]
In the world we live in,
not everyone
gets a second chance.
Sometimes, failing just once
means it's over for you.
You're done.
There's no way
to make up for it.
Be grateful
you were born a Zafra.
[DOOR OPENS]
Pa...
- I promise
- [FOOTSTEPS APPROACHING]
I won't fail you this time.
Prove it.
That's enough.
Mariano, let's go.
[LUCAS SIGHS]
[FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
[DOOR OPENS]
- [DOOR CLOSES]
- [FOOTSTEPS RETREATING]
[SOMBER MUSIC CONTINUES]
[DOOR OPENS]
Mr. Chan.
[KEYS JANGLING]
[GATE OPENS]
Where are you taking me?
I'm free now?
No.
We'll move you
to a new cell. Come.
Where?
- There.
- Where?
Oh, no, no, no!
Come on. Just go.
- That's enough.
- No! No!
That's an order from the bosses.
No!
Lock it.
[GATE CREAKS]
[KEYS JANGLING]
It's good.
We're together now.
No.
It's too bad.
Because only one of us
will come out of here alive.
[MUSIC TURNS GLUM]
[VICTOR GRUNTS SOFTLY]
[METAL RODS CLACKING]
[VICTOR] Who are you?!
What do you need from me?!
A huge bounty's been placed
on your head
for ruining the lives
of countless people.
You deserve to rot
behind bars!
- Aah!
- [BLOWS LANDING]
Whoever you are, you bastard,
you've no idea
who you're messing with.
The moment I get out of here,
I'll hunt you down.
I'll make you pay big time,
you fool.
[BIRDS CHIRPING IN DISTANCE]
[ISOBEL] Ricardo, everything is
ready for your gathering.
Well, I'm hoping one
of the guests
will help open doors
to potential investors.
I'll invite Pinky
so that she can help
encourage investors.
[RICARDO] Please do.
Isobel, there's only one thing
I want to happen today.
For them to see my life
after retiring.
That I'm still successful
despite having...
[INHALES DEEPLY]
having a daughter like Sam.
[SIGHS]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
She's part
of your success, Ricardo.
[HUFFS]
[TRAFFIC NOISE]
- I think this needs replacing.
- Hey, Rudy.
What are you doing out here?
Go get some rest.
Staying at home
makes me feel weaker.
Besides, I really want
to get back to work.
How could you not feel drained?
Betchay just won't stop
running her mouth.
[CHUCKLES SOFTLY]
Hold on, let me change
the subject...
Did you ever find out
who shot you?
[GLOOMY MUSIC PLAYING]
Honestly, I can't think
of anybody.
All I can remember is...
I was in the middle of a fight,
and then someone fired a gun.
I have no idea who it was.
You know,
I think my hunch is right.
Nobody else had a gun
except the police,
so I believe they're the ones
who shot you.
And remember that reporter?
- That... Salvador Manalo.
- Uh-- Yes, it's Salvador.
He witnessed everything
that day.
I keep seeing his face on TV,
calling out the police.
Yeah. That's why Betchay
was interviewed.
To get the full story.
[GLOOMY MUSIC CONTINUES]
Finally.
You kept your favorite agent
in check.
- I don't have favorites.
- Really?
[CHUCKLES DRYLY] That's funny.
Because if another person had
done those repeated offenses,
you would've sacked them
ages ago.
Samantha made a mistake,
and she'll be held
accountable for it.
But a single mistake can't undo
all the good she's brought
to the NCIA.
[PIA SCOFFS]
- A single mistake?
- [MOROSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Illegal arrest.
Unauthorized interrogation.
Assault on a witness.
Those are far
from simple mistakes, sir.
That's why she was suspended.
Yes, she's hard-headed.
But her principles are
harder still.
[MOROSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
She will bounce back.
She will learn from this.
Excuse me.
[MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
[HARRISS, STALLONE HUFFING]
[BROODING MUSIC PLAYING]
How's the training going?
- Ongoing, boss.
- That's right, boss.
- So, what's the plan?
- [MAN] Keep going.
Is it time to strike
Samantha Jacinto?
[LEE] Just tell us what
you want us to do with her.
We're ready anytime, boss.
We'll get back at her for you.
I'll take revenge for myself.
What, you think I can't do it?
Boss, we didn't mean it
like that.
Shut up!
I have to prove to Papa that
I can carry out his orders.
I can't afford another failure.
I have to redeem myself.
But Mama's right.
There's a proper time for this.
We'll strike Samantha Jacinto...
when she least expects it.
[MUSIC SWELLING]
[MUSIC ENDS]
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
De Luna!
- Ma'am.
- Come here.
Where is Sebastian?
He stepped out, ma'am.
Together with Ma'am Jacinto
and the whole team.
- Jacinto is with him?
- Yes, ma'am.
- Dismissed.
[MUSIC INTENSIFYING]
[MUSIC FADES, ENDS]
[DOOR OPENS]
[UNSETTLING MUSIC PLAYING]
[DOOR CLOSES]
We're here for your detainee,
Victor Zafra.
I'm the lawyer.
They're the family.
[POLICE OFFICER] You'll need
clearance to bring anyone else.
We're not just anybody.
Again,
we're the family
of Victor Zafra.
[LAWYER] What we're doing
isn't against the protocol.
- If we need clearance,
- [DOOR CLOSES]
then let us speak
with Director Delgado.
Understood. Just a moment.
[UNSETTLING MUSIC CONTINUES]
[MUSIC BECOMES TENSE]
[KNOCKING ON DOOR]
- Director.
- Yes?
Victor Zafra's parents are
waiting downstairs
with their lawyer.
[DELGADO] Hmm.
Are you saying
Col. Mariano Zafra is here?
Yes, sir. They're requesting
to see their son.
I'm sure they came here
to get their criminal son out.
- I'll deal with them.
- Yes, sir.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Mrs. Zafra.
Mariano.
[MARIANO SCOFFS]
Delgado!
You're still active
in the service?
Yes, I'm still active.
I'm still upholding the law
and standing for what's right.
Not like you.
All you have are allegations
against my son!
It's no surprise that
you're Victor's father.
The apple doesn't fall far
from the tree.
You still haven't changed.
You're still driven
by your own interests.
I haven't forgotten, Mariano,
how you ruined our operation
against the kidnapping ring!
That was a failure
on the NCIA's part!
My reputation
at the NLEA is solid,
from the day I entered service
until the day I retired!
Whatever you're planning
by coming here,
I'll make sure
you won't succeed.
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
We came here to talk to our son.
Not you.
- [OVERLAPPING CHATTER]
- [SHAKER RATTLING]
[WOMAN] Has someone
hit the jackpot yet?
Letter B number three!
- Has someone won yet?
- [SHAKER RATTLING]
[TENSE MUSIC PLAYING]
Hello.
Where's the money?
Boss Django...
The money I got is just enough
for my husband's funeral.
What's the point of
your husband's 3-month wake?
How will you pay me back?!
I just want to bury my husband.
Please,
let's put my father to rest.
Put to rest?
- [YELPS]
- Put to rest?
Do you want me to do
the same to your kid?
No, boss. Please!
You really don't have
the money?
Nothing?
[LAUGHS]
Nothing at all?
- [OBJECTS CLATTERING]
- [SCREAMING]
[MAN] Scram! All of you!
C'mon, Gabo.
You even meddled
with those kids' problem.
[BINOY] Those kids
were up to no good.
It's because their parents
aren't around.
That's the problem.
Their parents should
be around to care for them.
- You're right.
- To guide them.
You.
Find a way to give
my money back.
Do it now!
[WOMAN BREATHING HEAVILY]
Pray that your mother
gets the money,
or else you'll end up
like your father!
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [MAN GRUNTS]
[MAN] Help!
Someone take a video!
[TEKLA] Hey!
Watch where you're going!
[WOMAN] Gabo, please help me!
Django is causing trouble
at my husband's wake.
I haven't been able to bury
my spouse for 3 months
because he's claiming
all the money.
Gabo, we need to go.
- Why are we going there?
- We'll end up in trouble!
Pa...
Pray that your mother
gets me the money.
Or else,
you'll end up floating
in the river like your father!
Do you understand?!
[CRYING] Yes...
Django!
[TEKLA] Gabo,
let's just leave, please!
[TENSE MUSIC CONTINUES]
Gabo.
What the hell are you doing?
You really won't leave
the poor alone, won't you?
They're already poor,
and yet you're
still abusing them!
What do you guys want?
Do you want us to wipe
each other out here?!
Go ahead!
Until blood flows here in Tondo!
And only one group will be
left standing here!
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC PLAYING]
I'll count to three.
Or I'll end you.
One.
Two.
[SUSPENSEFUL MUSIC CONTINUES]
Three.
What happened to the NCIA?
Didn't they recognize you?
They might be looking for you!
Don't drag us with you!
We caught Mr. Chan,
but ended up in this situation.
You need to work with us
if you want to live.
Be our state witness
against Victor Zafra.
You probably already
snitched to the NCIA!
[GRUNTS]
We need to get Victor
out of there!
If we need to storm the NCIA
to break him out,
- I'll do it, Ma!
- Will you fight back?
- [BLOW LANDS]
- [GRUNTS]
We're the NCIA!
What if we finish you all off?!
If they file a complaint
against us,
we might end up suspended!
We might be able
to catch up to them!
- Gabo! Help!
- Help us, Gabo!